As we're now naming heat waves after
fossil fuel companies, I thought I'd
take a look back to the 22nd of May to
the first heatwave A for Aramco. Now,
Aramco are the largest oil producing
company in the world. And since 1965,
they've singlehandedly been able to
contribute over 4% of global carbon
emissions. But not all is lost because
they're currently investing $1.7 billion
into a carbon capture scheme. The first
phase of this should be ready by the end
of next year, 2027. And allegedly, it
will be able to capture up to 9 million
tons of carbon dioxide each year. Around
half of their annual carbon embissions.
Hm.
They would have been better off just
taking a day and a half off a year and
literally doing nothing and saving
themselves $1.7 billion. Uh because you
don't need to capture it if it's still
in the ground.
Anyway, the next heatwave will be named
after the letter C. So, what do you
reckon it should be called?